蒙特利尔航空航天博物馆
不如这样…
Okay. How about...
来份火箭热狗配太空薯片
a rocket dog with space chips?
陨石意面
Spaghetti with meteors?
银河葡萄杯
Galactic grape cup?
艾力奥 该吃东西了
Elio, you have to eat something.
还记得你妈妈总给你点什么吗
You remember what your mom used to order for you?
索利斯少校 您怎么在这儿
Major Solís, what are you doing here?
嘿 我陪侄子来的
Hey! Yeah, I'm with my nephew.
得哄这小祖宗吃饭
I'm trying to get him to eat.
说到这个…你侄子
Oh, right. Your nephew.
听说你兄嫂的事 我很难过
I heard about your brother and his wife. I'm so sorry.
谢谢关心
Thank you.
我们还在适应
We're managing.
那宇航员计划呢 你不是要…
What about the astronaut program? Weren't you about...
不去了
No. Not anymore.
现在不合适
The timing just isn't right.
我理解
Of course.
不过我和新室友处得挺开心
But it's been great spending time with my new roommate.
对吧 伙计
Right, buddy?
糟了
Oh, no.
"你好 我们是来自地球的小朋友"
Hello from the children of Planet Earth.
"从古至今"
Since the dawn of time,
"人类始终仰望星空思考"
humans have gazed at the stars and wondered...
"人类是否孤单"
are we alone?
"航行者号正是为了寻找答案"
Voyager is our attempt to find out.
"这位无畏的探索者肩负使命"
This intrepid explorer is on a mission,
"它将抵达人类未曾涉足的远方"
traveling farther than any human has ever gone,
"穿越宇宙最遥远的边界"
to the distant reaches of the cosmos and beyond.
"航行者号再也见不到创造它的人类"
Voyager will never see those who made it again.
"它将独自漂流 永恒航行"
It will drift on, solitary and alone.
"但或许某天"
But maybe one day,
"某个遥远世界会收到它的讯息"
distant worlds will receive its message
"届时航行者便完成了使命"
and Voyager will complete its mission,
"证明人类在宇宙中并不孤单"
proving we aren't so alone after all.
艾力奥 艾力奥
Elio! Elio!
艾力奥…
Elio...
你没事吧 怎么了
Are you hurt? What happened?
还好吗
What happened?
太空里真有其他生物吗 奥嘉姑妈
Is life really out there, Tía Olga?
啊
What?
该走了
Come on.
你不能突然跑掉 艾力奥
You can't run away like that, Elio.
"我代表加拿大政府及人民向你们问好"
I should like to extend the greetings of the government and the people of Canada.
"你好 我们是来自地球的小朋友"
Hello from the children of Planet Earth.
《外星奇遇记》
外星人 快绑架我
等一下
Oh, wait.
搞定了
Okay.
艾力奥
Elio!
暑假玩得开心点 记得看书!
加班 对不起 - 奥嘉姑姐
喂 外星人 绑架我吧
外星人看这边 求求你了
嘿
Hey.
你是艾力奥
Are you Elio?
你哪位啊
Who wants to know?
你贴告示说有业余无线电协会
You put flyers up for a Ham radio club?
我叫艾力奥・索利斯
I am Elio Solís,
业余无线电协会主席兼会长
president and leader of the Ham Radio Club
会址就在沙滩
of this beach.
厉害 我叫布斯
Cool. I'm Bryce.
太好了 牛啊…你带来了吗
Great, cool, awesome. Did you bring it?
有 是我爸爸的无线电机 但我有自己的代号
Oh, yeah. It's my dad's ham radio, but I have my own call sign.
叫 PXLOL
It's PXLOL,
但有时其他人听到会笑我
which sometimes makes people I talk to laugh.
最远联系到哪儿
How far have you called?
星期五时我联系到了…
On Friday I talked to...
俄亥俄州
Ohio.
我连接两部机 接收范围就翻倍
If I can pair these together, I can double their reach.
好了 你可以走了
Okay, you can go now.
走 等一下
Go? Wait.
其他人呢
Where's everyone else?
很遗憾 大部分会员突然得了…
Unfortunately, most of our members came down with...
失忆症…忘记来了
amnesia and forgot to come,
但三个月后的聚会再见
but I'll see you at the next meetup in three months!
-怎么样 布斯 -喂
- What's up, Bryce? - Hey.
一 二…
One, two...
你差点搞错
You almost messed up there.
嘿
Hey.
搞定
Oh, yeah.
牛啊
- Swoosh! - Nice.
他叫加纳 他也想来
This is Caleb. He wanted to come too.
嘿…你帽子怎么回事
Hey. What's with the hat?
我已经说过聚会要延期 带状疱疹不是开玩笑的
Like I said, the meetup's been postponed. Shingles is no joke.
你刚才说失忆症啊
I thought it was amnesia.
天啊 没错…还会传染呢
Oh, my gosh, you're right. It's spreading.
-再不走就会染上 拜拜 -那小孩搞什么
- You better go before you catch it. Bye! - Yo, what's up with this guy?
老兄 算了吧
Dude, chill.
他父母去世了
He's the kid whose parents died.
喂 那是机密消息
Hey, that's classified information.
身为无线电协会会长 我要…
As leader of this radio club, I hereby...
你弄的
Did you do that?
别碰
No.
-这样正常吗 -别碰 停手
- Is this supposed to happen? - Don't. Stop it!
哈罗 哈罗 听得到吗
Hello? Hello? Can you hear me?
-给我看看 -你别碰
- Let me see that. - Don't touch that.
-我想看看 -我要回复呀
- I was just looking at it. - I have to respond.
-放手 -别这样
- Let go! - Quit it.
不要啊
No!
喂 这可不能怪我啊
Yo, that was not my fault.
我根本没想…
I didn't mean to...
不会吧
Oh, come on.
你这飞不出太空 满肚子废气的…
You suborbital, gaseous...
太空垃圾
waste of mass!
超新星爆发程序启动
Activate supernova blast!
滚开啦 你个怪咖
Get off of me, you freak.
-你们两个住手 -他咬我
- Come on, guys, stop! - He bit me!
喂 你们几个在搞什么
Hey, what are you doing?
你疯了吗
Unbelievable!
在沙滩打架 还逃学
Fighting on the beach, skipping school?
是不是要我给你们装追踪器
Am I going to have to put a tracker on you?
还有你的眼睛
Now your eye.
医生说两周内不准碰
The doctor said not to touch it for two weeks.
艾力奥
Elio!
我是说立刻马上
You meant starting now.
我是认真的 你脑子里到底在想什么
This is serious! What were you thinking?
我本来一个人好好晒着月亮
I was minding my own business, taking in the night air
-突然两个捣蛋鬼就袭击我 -少来这套
- and suddenly these ruffians attacked me. - No, no, no.
求你看着我的眼睛说真话
Look at me in the eye and for once, tell me the truth.
对不起
停 我才不学"艾力奥语"
No. I'm not learning Elioese.
学两句嘛
索利斯少校
Major Solís.
今晚研讨会你去吗
You going to the seminar tonight?
宇航员选拔计划会派专员来做简报
There'll be a speaker from the Astronaut Selection Program.
不 不去了
No. No, no.
家里有事
Something came up.
噢 这就是你常提起的侄子
Oh, is this the nephew we've heard so much about?
没错 就是他
Yes, that's him.
够了
- Gloodle! - Stop it!
你是在试探我的底线 还是单纯没睡醒
I don't know if this is boundary testing, or sleep regression, or...
你现在属于哪种状态
Which one of these is you?
我不知道 但你看起来像这种
I don't know, but I think that one is you.
好吧…我要开最后一个会
Okay, I've got one last meeting.
你给我老实坐着
So, I need you to sit here
不许动 不许说话
and not move or speak
也别弄伤自己 就乖十分钟
or injure yourself for 10 minutes.
我已经够忙了
I have enough to deal with already.
为什么突然召开紧急会议
What's with this emergency meeting?
你没听说传闻
Oh, you didn't hear?
阿唛说他发现了外星人
Melmac thinks he found aliens.
有好戏看咯
This ought to be good.
好了 阿唛先生 请开始报告
All right, Mr. Melmac, let's hear it.
少校…
Major...
索利斯少校 此前…
Major Solís, earlier today,
我从星际空间接收到这段信号
I found this signal coming from interstellar space.
阿唛 别闹了
Melmac, please.
-很晚了… -等等
- It's late... - Wait, wait, wait.
你仔细听
Listen closely.
你好 地球
Hello, Planet Earth.
1977年 美国宇航局发射了…
In 1977, NASA launched the...
-金唱片 -金唱片 没错
- The Golden Record. - The Golden Record! Yes.
-什么 -金唱片 长官
- The what? - The Golden Record, sir,
就像地球的漂流瓶
was Earth's message in a bottle.
哈罗 我们是来自地球的小朋友
Hello from the children of Planet Earth.
看到了吗
Don't you see?
你好 地球
Hello, Planet Earth.
我觉得星际空间有人收到了信号
I think someone in interstellar space found our message
然后给我们发回了回复
and is sending it back to us as a reply!
-阿唛 -少校
- Melmac... - Major...
- Melmac... - Major!
这次不能当没看见 必须回复
We can't just leave it like this, we have to respond.
我已经调整所有卫星准备发送回应
I've already rerouted every satellite to send the signal back.
可能会引发系统故障
Sure, it might cause a few system failures.
对不起…说不定会短路起火
Whoop. Sorry. Maybe a small electrical fire,
但换来第一次接触就太值了
but it would be worth it for first contact!
万事俱备 就等你开口
I have everything cued up and ready to go. Just say the word!
如果有人 或者有什么…想联系地球
If someone or something is calling out to Earth,
你想让谁代表地球去回复
who on Earth do you want taking that call?
你…
You...
回家吧
should go home.
-放一周假 -放两周
- Take a week. - Take two weeks.
别这样…大家要相信我
No. You got to believe me.
少校 求你了 真的有外星人
Major, please! They're out there!
少校
Major!
放开我
Unhand me!
我想提醒各位 我们是轨道分析员
May I remind everyone that we are orbital analysts.
负责追踪太空垃圾 而不是模糊的UFO信号
We track space debris, not rogue UFO signals.
要不大家…
Let's just...
休息五分钟吧
Let's just take five.
今晚太辛苦了
It's been a long night.
真是个疯子
What a nutjob.
我是来自地球的艾力奥·索利斯
This is Elio Solís of the planet Earth.
我没有恶意
I come in peace...
而且超级想加入你们
and I'm super excited to join you.
我有创意 勤奋…
I'm creative, hardworking...
还很壮实
shredded.
快来接我 我等着
So please come and get me. I'll be waiting.
好啦 拜拜 爱你
Okay, bye. Love you.
太棒了
Yes.
Yes!
太好了
糟了
Oh, no.
时间紧迫 外星人随时会到 要收拾行李
Time is of the essence. They could be here any minute. I got to pack!
我会负全责…但你也有孩子吧
I take full responsibility, but, I mean, you have kids, right?
我很快就走 别担心
I'll be out of your way soon. Don't worry.
-就带几包零食 -艾力奥
- Just need a few snacks for the road. - Elio!
对不起 长官…你说什么
Sorry, ma'am. What was that?
你不介意少哪包 辣味
Which will you miss the least? ¿Fuego?
-就辣味吧 -我明白
- Fuego. Yeah. - I understand.
要带叉子 会被当成武器
Should I bring forks, or would they think they're weapons?
别冒险 带勺子吧
Not worth the risk! I'll bring spoons.
又漂亮又和平的勺子
Nice, peaceful spoons.
-我的帅斗篷呢 -你也是 长官
- Where's my good cape? - You too, ma'am.
-洗了 -多谢
- It's not in the wash, is it? - Thank you.
-在这里 -艾力奥…
- Here it is! - Elio...
蓝色还是绿色 哪种颜色代表"带我走"
Blue or green? Which one says, "Take me with you,"
但又不太着急
but not in a desperate way?
艾力奥停下 求你了
Elio, stop! Please!
外星人不会来接你
Aliens are not coming for you.
但那个人说…
But that guy said...
你完全失控…你和人打架
You're out of control. You got in a fight.
还让整个基地停电
You shut down power to the whole base
我差点被炒鱿鱼
and I almost lost my job!
我们要试试其他方式
We have to try something different.
寄宿学校 你想赶我走
Boarding school? You're trying to get rid of me.
不 只是夏令营 就几个星期
No, this is just their sleepaway camp. It's just a couple of weeks.
我不能去 外星人今晚会来
I can't go. They're coming tonight.
你需要交几个朋友 一个也好啊
You need to make friends or just a friend.
我不想要朋友 我只想见外星人
I don't care about friends. I need to meet aliens.
为什么
Why?
因为外太空有五亿个宜居星球
Because there's 500 million habitable planets out there
总有一个愿意收留我 因为你显然就不想
and one of them's got to want me! Because obviously you don't!
我当然想 我们是一家人
Of course, I do! We're family!
你不是我家人
You're not my family!
你的生活不在太空 艾力奥
Your life isn't up there, Elio.
而是在地球
It's down here.
我搞不定
I can't deal with this.
有谁能搞得定
I don't know if anybody can deal with this.
我明天会送他过去
When I drop him off tomorrow,
问问下学期能否入学
I'm going to see if they can enroll him in the fall.
我知道
I know,
但我从没想过我的人生会是这样
but this just isn't how I thought my life would be.
这是古老的人类主题
It's an ancient human theme.
几乎所有文化中都找得到
You can find it in virtually every culture,
包括宗教 民谣 迷信
in religion, folklore, superstition
直到现今的科学
and now in science.
在这个时代去寻找其他生物很特别
The search for life elsewhere is remarkable in our age,
因为我们是首次可以实际行动
because this is the first time that we can actually do something
不再只是空想
besides speculation.
我们可以送太空船去邻近星球
We can send spacecraft to nearby planets.
可以用大型电波望远镜
We can use large radio telescopes
观察最近有没有讯息传来
to see if there is any message being sent to us lately...
而这一切为解答人类最想知道的问题
and it touches to the deepest of human concerns.
人类是否孤单
Are we alone?
别过来
No contact! No contact!
你知道吗 我小时候也参加过
You know I went here too, when I was a kid.
你这刻可能不相信…
You might not believe me right now...
不过这里会对你有好处
but this will be good for you.
-杜鲁门辅导员 聊两句 -没问题 少校
- Counselor Truman, could I have a word? - Of course, Major.
我们俩惹上麻烦了…
We got in so much trouble...
都是因为你
because of you.
没错 多谢你啊
Yeah. Thanks a lot.
-你小心点 -知道啦
- Better watch your back. - Yeah.
他肯定会被吓一跳
He's going to be so freaked out!
按我说的做
Follow my lead.
安静…再静点
Quiet. Quiet.
不会伤到他吧 只是吓唬一下
We're not going to hurt him, right? Just scare him a little?
来吧 肯定很有趣
Come on, it'll be funny.
闭嘴 你会吵醒他的 快走
Shut up! You'll wake him up. Come on.
安静 再小声点
Quiet, quiet!
你好 地球人
Greetings, Earthling.
我们没有恶意
We come in peace!
他去哪了
Where did he go?
雅典娜五号 废弃卫星正漂向你那边
Athena 5, there is a decommissioned satellite headed your way.
正在计算新航线 请稍等
I'm calculating a new flight path for you. Standby.
请讲 基地
Go ahead, Montez.
减53 再加32 转向7度
Minus 53, plus 32, roll seven.
明白 收到
Yeah, copy that.
抱歉吓到你了
Sorry about the scare.
今天很多卫星干扰航线
There's been a lot of satellite interference today.
收到 雅典娜五号结束通话
Roger that. Athena 5, over and out.
一切顺利
艾力奥
Elio!
-出来吧 别躲了 -艾力奥
- Come out, come out, wherever you are! - Elio!
-不想一起玩吗 -不是说想认识外星人
- Don't you want to hang out with us? - I thought you wanted to meet some aliens.
出来吧 肯定很好玩
Come on, it'll be fun.
他肯定在附近
He's out here somewhere.
出来 太空小子 我们知道你在附近
Come on, Space Boy! We know you're out there.
带
你们的领袖
过来
带你们的领袖过来
拜托
抓到你了
Gotcha!
你们找到我了
You found me.
我们要报仇
This is payback.
不用了 下次再报吧
It's okay. You don't need to pay me back.
等等…那是什么
Wait. What is that?
希望你喜欢吃
Hope you like how it tastes.
后面有东西啊
There's something back there.
快看
Look!
你完蛋了 索利斯
You're so dead, Solís.
抓住他
Hey, hold on.
等一下
Wait.
求你了
Please.
太棒了
Yes!
好极了
真的来了 来接我
It's happening! It's really happening.
我就知道一定会
I knew it! I knew it!
太棒了
Yes!
酷毙了
Yes, yes, yes!
谢谢
Thank you!
太好玩了
Yes! Yeah!
嗨
Hi.
我早说过 我早知道外星人会找我 你救了我一命
I knew it! I knew aliens were looking for me. You saved my life!
我保证我会尽力帮助…这艘飞船
I promise I'll pull my weight on this spaceship?
这是飞船吗 要怎么做
Is this a spaceship? Anyway, where should we start?
用探针 采集样本
Probes? Samples?
我全身都是样本
I've got plenty.
测试…测试…
Testing, testing, testing.
现在能听懂吗
Can you understand me now?
能听懂…太神了
Yes. Wow.
很高兴认识你
It is a pleasure to meet you.
我叫"呜呼呼"是液态超级电脑
I am Ooooo, a liquid supercomputer.
先帮你调节重力
Allow me to adjust your gravity.
-不用 我习惯了 -重力开启
- Oh, no, no, no. I'm fine. - Gravity on.
请你喝杯欢迎"果粒"由宇宙联盟免费提供
A welcome glass of glorp, compliments of the Communiverse.
谢谢
Thank you.
等等 什么联盟
Wait. The what?
欢迎来到宇宙联盟
Welcome to the Communiverse,
一个由不同银河系 各种高阶生物组成的联合组织
a pangalactic organization of the advanced species of the cosmos.
全宇宙最聪明的生命体 都会来分享知识 新概念
The greatest minds of the universe come here to share knowledge, innovation...
还有食谱
And recipes!
欢迎
Welcome!
-欢迎 -太棒了
- Welcome! - Lovely.
你们好 各位大使
Greetings, Ambassadors!
非常兴奋见到你们
Absolutely ecstatic to make your acquaintance.
你喝光了呢…我给你续杯 兄弟
You've run dry. Let me top you off, old brick.
谢谢
Thank you.
厉害 一个小脑 四个脑叶
Yes. One cerebellum, four lobes...
还有骨髓
and a medulla.
介意我伸进去看看吗
Do you mind if I take a little peek inside and see?
姬丝塔 别急着读心 今天才刚认识
Questa, don't mindread him, you've just met him.
我很抱歉
So sorry about that.
我是光星的姬丝塔
I am Questa of Gom.
法拉临门的希历士
Helix of Falluvinum.
塔门的塔文
Tegmen of Tegmeg.
你呢
And you are?
艾力奥·索利斯来 自地…地球
Elio Solís of, uh... Earth!
为新候选人干杯 敬"地地球"的艾力奥·索利斯
A toast to our new candidate, Elio Solís of Uh- Earth.
-他到了 -艾力奥·索利斯
- There he is! - Elio Solís!
快看 是艾力奥
Look, it's Elio!
新候选人
It's a new candidate!
欢迎
Salutations!
我喜欢你的眼睛
I love your eye!
我们一直在宇宙寻找志同道合的新物种
We search the universe for like- minded souls and new species
我们觉得你绝对是 宇宙联盟的完美候选成员
and we think you're an excellent candidate for Communiverse membership.
你是说我可以留下
You mean I could stay here?
只要全体会员同意就行
If all the members agree, then, yes.
到时候你就是我们的一员 还能荣幸地佩戴这枚徽章
You'll be one of us and be the proud bearer of one of these.
来啊 大家都想认识你
Now come, everyone's eager to meet you.
我们每个人都带着独特的知识和兴趣来分享
Each of us brings our specialized knowledge and interest to share.
你好啊 莱丝
Greetings, Naos!
你好 幸会
Hello. Salutations.
莱丝发明了宇宙控制器 大家都用它来调节重力
Naos, here, created the Communidiscs we all use with controls for gravity...
温度
temperature...
以及翻译所有已知语言
and all known languages.
你会说"艾力奥语"
You know Elioese?
连脏话都会
最后一个词我都没听过!
-再见 -再见
- Gloodle! - Gloodle!
拜拜
Gloodle!
这是我最新设计 你试试
This is my most recent design. Try it.
你好
Hello.
我是宇宙使用说明书
I am the Universal Users Manual.
我知晓宇宙所有奥秘
I contain the secrets of the universe.
生命的意义
What is the meaning of life?
黑洞里有什么 执着于目标只会…
What lies beyond a black hole? Is there a purpose to...
谁会赢
Who would win in a fight?
拿着棒球棍的大猩猩 还是十只黑猩猩
One gorilla with a baseball bat or ten chimps?
打架…从来就没有真正的赢家
None who fight are true winners.
大猩猩
The gorilla.
这些小家伙叫迷你毛丝
These little critters are mimollusks.
能用纳米技术造出任何你想要的东西
They use nanotechnology to construct anything you desire.
开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
太酷了
How dashing!
这里是我见过最美的地方
This is the most beautiful place I've ever seen.
这里是…厕所
This is the bathroom.
每次都这么好玩
Gets me every time.
太棒了
Bracing.
我天生就该属于这里
It's like I was always meant to be here.
我早知道你们在找我
I knew you were looking for me.
我们当然一直在寻找你
Of course we were looking for you.
收到你寄来的可爱迷你飞船就开始找了
Ever since we picked up this charming little spacecraft you sent us.
航行者号
Voyager?
我们在小行星带发现了它
We found it in an asteroid field.
做工非常精良
Nice craftsmanship.
真的吗
Thanks?
我们想知道是谁制造了它 所以发出了邀请
Curious about the species who made it, we sent an invitation
很高兴收到你们星球的正式回复
and were delighted to receive your planet's official reply.
我是地球的艾力奥·索利斯 超级渴望加入你们
This is Elio Solís of the planet Earth and I'm super excited to join you.
我有创意 勤奋 还特别强壮
I'm creative, hardworking, shredded.
快来接我吧 我等着 好啦 拜拜 爱你
So, please come and get me. I'll be waiting. Okay, bye. Love you.
-真感人 -我们非常高兴…
- Very touching. - We are delighted
终于见到你了
to finally make your acquaintance,
地地球的领袖
Leader of Uh- Earth.
你脸怎么这么红
Why is your face melting?
-因为… -各位大使
- Well... - Ambassadors,
有件重要事需要各位处理
an urgent matter requires your attention.
是关于另一位候选人的
It involves the other candidate.
-是他 -天啊
- Oh, him. - Oh, dear.
快过去 必须尽快
We should hurry. Quickly now!
失陪了
Excuse us.
大家一起去吧
Please join us.
各位的科技加上我的武器 就能组成无敌同盟
Your technology and my weapons would be an unstoppable alliance.
立刻批准我加入宇宙联盟
Now, admit me to your Communiverse!
很遗憾 格尔钢候选人
Unfortunately, Candidate Grigon,
经过评估后 你…
it is our assessment that you are
不符合加入条件
not a fit.
我…格尔钢勋爵
I, Lord Grigon,
高拿族的鲜血帝王…不够格
Blood Emperor of Hylurg, not a fit?
我们崇尚互相包容 保持开放…
Well, we believe in tolerance and open- mindedness...
我已经够包容了
I am tolerant!
抱歉 不是你的问题
So sorry, it's not you.
是联盟的问题
It's us.
不是说它问题很大吗
I thought we said it was him.
如果我不能加入宇宙联盟
If I cannot join the Communiverse,
就用武力解决
then I shall take it by force!
准备接受我的征服吧
Prepare to be conquered!
太暴力了
What a brute!
为什么非要开个新洞
Why did he make a new hole?
我建议大伙逃命躲起来
I suggest we run and hide.
好啊 一起去宇宙边缘 把灯全关了
Yes, let's go to the edge of the cosmos and turn off all the lights.
包括我 对吧
That includes me, right?
非常抱歉 索利斯候选人
Oh, so sorry, candidate Solís,
目前情况下 我们无法接纳新成员
we couldn't possibly accept new members under the current situation.
申请无限期搁置
Applications are closed indefinitely.
-可我才刚到 -真遗憾
- But I just got here! - Such a shame.
要不你几千年后再申请
Let's check back in a few thousand years?
不如去找格尔钢勋爵谈谈
Perhaps one of us could talk to Lord Grigon.
-你去啊 -我才不去
- You do it! - Not me.
-我害羞 -我很忙
- I am shy. - I'm busy.
-我过敏 -我快没电了
- I have allergies. - My battery is low.
别担心 我会送你回地球 继续原来的生活
Don't worry. I'll return you to your life on Uh- Earth just as it was.
原来的生活
Just as it was.
不要…不要啊
No, no!
我去
I'll do it.
我是地球的领袖
I'm the leader of Earth.
绝对是最佳人选
I'm the perfect guy for the job.
他说什么语言
What did it say?
-真奇怪 -想不明白
- How curious. - I do not understand.
-你愿意找格尔钢勋爵谈谈 -打算怎么谈
- You would talk to Lord Grigon? - But what would you say?
你是解决冲突的专家
Are you an expert on conflict negotiation?
那当然 我的人生全是冲突
You kidding? My life is nothing but conflict...
还有战斗伤疤作证
and I've got the battle scars to prove it.
这次终于不一样了
It would be a welcome change
不用再每次遇到恶霸都逃跑
not to flee every bully who covets our treasures.
他真的信得过
没错 你有什么好处
Yes. What's in it for you?
为什么你肯接受这危险任务
Why would you agree to such a dangerous mission?
因为…
Because...
你们需要我
you need me.
而且我都一把年纪 是时候回馈社会
And at my age it's really about giving back.
如果你成功劝退格尔钢 我们就立即批准你加入
If you can make Grigon go away, we'd make you a member on the spot.
那我身为地球的领袖 准备好为大家效劳
Then I, the leader of Earth, am ready to serve.
-太棒了 非常好 -厉害呀
- Good. Very good. - How impressive!
-好勇敢 -太好了
- What courage! - Wonderful!
索利斯候选人 你果然充满惊喜
Candidate Solís, you continue to surprise.
当格尔钢再来时 我们会做好准备
When Grigon returns, we shall be ready for him.
现在 正如地球人所讲
Until then, as you say on Uh- Earth.
好啦 拜拜 爱你
Okay, bye. I love you.
Okay. Bye. I love you.
放心 交给我
Don't worry. I got this.
有我就没问题
You're in great hands.
还有一件事
Just one last order of business.
好 你说吧
Oh, yeah, of course.
当你跟军阀谈判时 要有替身扮演你
While you negotiate with the warlord, you'll need a temporary replacement.
介意我采DNA样本吗
Can I trouble you for a DNA sample?
没问题 你想怎样…
Sure. Where do you want it...?
哇 我第一次采样呀
Wow. My first probe.
你这样的世界领袖 不可以突然失踪
World leaders, such as yourself, can't just disappear.
否则你的星球会大乱
Your planet would descend into chaos.
所以复制泥帮到你
That's what cloning clay is for.
这是…
Is this...?
你是…
Are you...?
我
Me?
包…
Rock...
剪…
Paper...
黑洞
Black hole!
-太空好棒 -太空最酷
- Space is the best! - Space is amazing!
进去吧
In you go.
对不起呀
Sorry.
讨生活就是这样
It's a living.
那…我有什么目标
So, what is my motivation?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我要改变一下
Should I change anything
还是做回没自信 渴望找到归属感的你
or just stick with the low self- esteem and desperation to belong?
啊 我很正常 你正正常常就行
What? I'm normal, just be normal.
别做奇葩事 懂吗
No weird stuff, okay?
-明白 -好极了
- Okay. - Okay.
玩开心点
Have fun.
地球的习俗真有趣…军阀在等你
Intriguing Uh- Earth custom. The warlord awaits.
我想复习一下再过去
There was just a few things I wanted to brush up on.
什么都知道的那东西呢
Where was that thing that knew everything about everything?
你指这个
You mean this?
哈罗 我是宇宙用户说明书
Hello. I am the Universal Users Manual.
你想知道生命的意义 其实…
Would you like to learn the meaning of life now? It's a...
不是 我想知道怎么跟凶狠对手谈判
No. I need everything you've got on how to negotiate with the warmonger.
没问题
Certainly.
-我有几章讲同理心 -不要
- I have chapters on leading with empathy. - Nope.
-促进双方关系 -不要
- Fostering connection? - Nope.
赶尽杀绝的交易
Making the killer deal?
就是这个 有笔吗
Yes, that one. Do you have a pen?
看来你牺牲的几率越来越高了
In the increasingly likely event that you will die,
需要先通知你在地球的家属吗
would you like to notify your next of kin on Uh- Earth?
不 不需要
No, that's okay.
一开始就要有霸气
Start from a position of power.
最重要的是保持冷静
The most important thing is to stay calm.
别再叫我保持冷静
Don't you tell me to stay calm!
有没有搞错 这是露营还是格斗会
What is this, huh? A camp or a fight club?
他只是个天真的小朋友
He's an innocent little boy
如果你说这样叫培养性格
and if this is what you call building character,
我一定会去找你老板投诉
then I'll take it up with your boss,
或者找他老板…所有人的老板
or her boss. Everyone's boss!
太离谱了
Unacceptable!
下次再来玩!
我不该丢下你
I never should have left you here.
没错 他们追打我 因为我又瘦又矮
Yeah, they chased me because I'm weak and small,
不过晚餐有披萨吃 整体还算挺开心
but there was pizza for dinner. So, overall, a pretty good night.
你眼睛怎样 有没有肿
How's the eye? Swollen?
-有没有伤到 -没事
- Did they hurt it? - It's fine.
对不起 我昨晚没找你
I'm so sorry I didn't check in.
-因为有怪事发生 -没关系
- Something weird was happening. - That's okay.
我要追踪来自太空的奇怪信号…
I was tracking this crazy signal from space...
在回家路上 晚餐吃什么
Are we going home? What's for dinner?
芝士焗通心粉
Mac and cheese.
我以为你会有兴趣听 如果真有外星人从太空发信号…
I just thought you'd be interested because if aliens were calling from space...
今日清晨沿岸多云有雾
Early morning fog and clouds along the coast...
艾力奥
Elio?
普通芝士还是白切达芝士 我好饿
Are we doing regular or white cheddar? I'm starved.
你不想聊外星人
So, you don't want to talk about aliens?
不想 最好永远都别提
Not really. I thought it'd be better if I just dropped it.
你说真的
Really?
那…太好了
That's... amazing.
对你是好事
Good for you.
我好喜欢这首歌
I love this song.
看到他吗
Do you see him?
看到 他带了好多…
Yes, and he's brought his...
同伴
compatriots.
这次精彩了
Jolly good.
好了 要有自信 要有霸气
Okay. Be confident. Speak from a position of power.
他来了
He's here!
他来了 终于到了
He's here. There he is.
我们的大救星
The man of the hour.
抱歉迟到
Sorry I'm late.
格尔钢勋爵会过来
So, is Lord Grigon coming here?
不 是你要过去
Oh, no. You will be going out there.
好啦 拜拜 爱你
Okay, bye. Love you.
这是什么鬼按钮
What is this?
红色 绿色
Red? Green?
欢迎 索利斯船长
Welcome, Captain Solís.
你已选择我方坐标地图
You have selected a map of our coordinates.
船舱压力 防护罩系统 营养奶昔 薄荷糖
Cabin pressure. Shield function. A nutritious shake. A breath mint.
清理膀胱模式
A bladder evacuation module.
他找到薄荷糖了
He found the mint.
你已设定家乡星球为目的地
You have set our destination to your home planet.
地…地球
Uh- Earth.
确认 还是取消
Confirm or cancel?
祝你好运
Good luck.
取消
Cancel.
好啦…我能行的
Okay, okay.
再往左一点点
A little to the left.
双手握住十点和两点钟方向
Get your nubs at ten and two.
他简直像个英雄
What a heroic figure he cuts.
嗨 带我去见你们的领袖
Hi. Take me to your leader?
好了 盯住他眼睛 要够气势
Okay, look him in the eye. Stand your ground.
你是老大 你最厉害 你…
You're the alpha, you're the killer. You're...
宇宙联盟就派你来
This is who the Communiverse sends?
你比我想象中更矮小
You are more puny than I expected.
你也差不多
I could say the same about you.
你说什么
What?
怎样才肯放过宇宙联盟
What do you need to leave the Communiverse alone?
高拿族喜欢听着尖叫声谈判
Hylurgians prefer to negotiate with screams in the air.
发射
Pull!
后坐力有点大
Recoil's a little heavy.
该你了
Your turn.
糟 我把手臂枪落家里了
Darn! I left my arm cannon at home.
要不我们…
Why don't we...?
我借你一支
Use one of mine.
你人真好
So nice of you.
大家都是领袖 而且…
I mean, we're both leaders and...
发射
Pull!
双方一定能找到办法…
Surely we could find something to everyone's mutual...
双赢的
benefit.
玩花样是吧
Trick shot.
或许我能和你沟通…发射
Perhaps we are able to communicate... Pull!
但那些宇宙联盟的弱者
But those Communiverse weaklings
个个都当我是怪物
look at me like some kind of monster.
他们竟敢拒绝我
How dare they reject me!
如果他们不要你…
Well, if they don't want you,
引起敌人共鸣
不如找个需要你的地方
why not find someone who does?
你再说一遍
Come again?
肯定还有其他地方…
There's got to be a place out there
超需要你这种强壮猛男
that would love to have a strong guy like you.
但宇宙联盟聚集了所有伟大领袖
But is the Communiverse not where the greatest leaders gather?
我不够伟大吗
Am I not great?
当然够啦
Totally.
但为什么要浪费时间 跟不懂你的人沟通
But why waste your life trying to connect with people who don't get you?
你是时候向前看了
It's time to move on.
对吧 钢…哥
Right, Gri- guy?
钢哥
Gri- guy?
没错…又怎么了 伟高
Yes. What, Workko, what is it?
血刃殿下 小王子想见您
Your Wrath, the princeling wants to see you.
气死我了…告诉他我很忙
For the hate of the... Tell him I am busy!
继续刚才的话题…别再管宇宙联盟
So, as we were saying, forget the Communiverse...
你不是当爸爸了吗
You are a father, right?
是啊
Yeah.
当爹太难了
It is so difficult!
他完全不懂我的工作有多重要
He has no concept of the importance of my work.
我太懂了 搞不定就送走呗
I get it. If he's too hard to handle, then just ship him off.
我也是这么干的 所以…
That's what I did with mine. So...
"搞不定"
"Too hard to handle"?
我是说…
I mean...
你觉得我管不了自己儿子
You think I cannot handle my own son?
不是 我没这意思
No, no, no. I don't think that...
那你倒说说 我哪里做错了
No! Really. Tell me what I am doing wrong!
无所谓啦 我当家长也很烂
It's okay. I'm a bad parent too.
-什么 -大家本来就不会当父母
- What? - None of us know what we're doing.
而且根本不想当 对吧
We didn't even want this, right?
让我提醒你在跟谁谈判
Let me remind you who you are dealing with!
我是格尔钢 高拿族的血刃帝王…
I am Grigon, Blood Emperor of Hylurg...
蟹状星云的灾星 而且是个好爸爸
scourge of the Crab Nebula and a great father!
放屁
Pull!
好吧 咱们都冷静点…
Right, why don't we take a little breather...
谈判结束…卫兵
The negotiation is over. Gronk!
把囚犯押去地牢
Show the prisoner to his quarters!
囚犯 什么
Prisoner? What?
你会被关在地牢 眼睁睁看我毁掉你心爱的宇宙联盟
You will watch from a cell as I destroy your beloved Communiverse!
不要 等等啊
No, no, wait!
他完全变了个人
He's really turned over a new leaf.
-嘿 艾力奥 -嗨 阿占 你背伤怎么样了
- Hey, Elio. - Hey, Jim. How's your back?
-你知道的… -懂的
- Oh, you know... - I hear ya.
那个夏令营真管用
Camp must've really helped.
我想也是
I guess it did.
但他只待了一天
But he was only there for one day.
我偷听到上校夸你呢
I overheard the colonel raving about you.
真的 她真夸了
Really? She was?
真的 你最近特别勤快
Yeah. You've been working really hard.
太好了 还以为再也翻不了身
That's so good to hear. I thought I'd never get off her bad side.
大家对你都很满意
Everyone's super impressed.
等等 求你了 你弄错了
Wait, please. You made a mistake.
我是地球的领袖
I'm the leader of Earth!
重力…关闭
Gravity... off.
好了…重力恢复
Okay, that's enough! Gravity back!
我得回去找格尔钢 还有什么没试
Okay. I'll just get back to Grigon. What haven't I tried?
"谈判筹码" 就是贵重物品
"Bargaining chip"? Like, something valuable?
我要去哪里找…
Where am I going to find...?
嗨 你好呀
Hi, there.
我还年轻不想死…
I'm too young to die. I'm too young to die.
我还年轻不想死啊…
I'm too young to die.
什么事 搞什么呀
What's happening? What's happening?
翻译机呀 厉害
Translator disc, cool.
-你会吃我 -哈
- Are you going to eat me? - What?
我看你太害怕才裹住你
I was just swaddling you because you seemed scared.
如果我害怕 妈妈也会裹住我
That's what my mom does when I get scared.
我很少没被裹着
I'm rarely unswaddled.
你只是个小孩子
You're just a little kid.
那又怎样 你这么说太没礼貌
So? Don't have to be rude about it.
不是呀 喂 回来啊
No, no, no. Hey, come back!
我不是笑你
I wasn't making fun of you!
我叫艾力奥
My name's Elio.
你呢
What's your name?
你真想知道我的名字
You really want to know my name?
我…比较想先着地
Well, I really want to get down.
我叫歌尔顿 从来没人问过我名字
I'm Glordon! No one's ever asked me my name before.
我经常问很多问题
I mean, I ask a lot of questions all the time.
但没人问过关于我的事
No one ever asks me about questions about me, though.
比如我最喜欢的颜色
Like what my favorite color is.
是紫色 如果你想问…你想问吗
It's purple, if you're asking. Are you asking?
干嘛啦 只是我的盔甲外壳
What's wrong with you? That's just my carapace.
-哈 -我给你看看
- What? - I'll show you.
你看
Ta- da!
每个高拿族人长大后都会有一套
Every Hylurgian gets one when they come of age.
配有武器 炸弹 各种小配件
It's got weapons and bombs and stuff.
还有杯架
Ooh, and a cup holder!
量身定做的
It's bespoke.
所以…如果高拿族脱下盔甲 就和你差不多
So, if Hylurgians took off their armor, they'd look like you?
没错 但没族人会脱盔甲
Yeah, but nobody would ever do that.
因为暴露自己柔软 温暖的身体
To expose your soft, warm flesh
会永远令自己和家族蒙羞
would dishonor you and your whole family for all eternity.
我好期待穿盔甲呀
I can't wait to get installed.
我一定会很帅气
I'm going to look so hot.
警报 有囚犯逃脱
Alert! A prisoner has escaped.
-糟了 -在说你吗
- Oh, no. - Are they talking about you?
整件事是复杂的政治问题 你不会明白
It's a complicated political situation. You wouldn't understand.
-你是星球的叛徒 -去哪了
- Are you a treacherous dissident? - Where is he?
-检查每个房间 -你是杀手
- Check every chamber! - Are you an assassin?
-你们两个跟着我 走 -你做了什么
- You two with me. Move! - What'd you do?
明白 长官
Yes, sir!
说吧 我最会保守秘密
Come on, I'm really good at keeping secrets.
-没发现 -继续找
- Nothing here, sir. - Keep looking!
秘密就是…
The secret is...
我也是小孩子
I'm a kid.
哈 真的
What? Really?
真的
Mm- hmm.
我骗了宇宙联盟…
And I kind of tricked the Communiverse into thinking I was the leader of Earth.
-什么 -别管他们
- What? - Just leave them alone
否则我就会被抓住
or else I'm going to be captured
离开我唯一想去的地方
out of the only place I've ever wanted to be.
不会吧 你疯了吗
No way! You're crazy.
我知道 现在格尔钢想炸死所有人
I know and now Grigon's going to blow everyone up
除非我能找到谈判筹码
unless I can find a bargaining chip.
他最珍视的东西…但他珍视什么
Something he values, but what does he even value?
我爸喜欢鲜血 荣耀和折磨敌人
Well, Dad values blood, glory, the misery of his enemies.
-有次… -等等
- There was this one time... - Hold up.
格尔钢是你父亲
Grigon's your dad?
我以为你知道 我和他长得一模一样
I thought you knew. I look just like him.
你仔细看
Check it out.
谈判筹码
我最近练了背肌
I've been working on my back.
你能不能…帮我个大忙
Can I ask you a big favor?
当然可以
Sure.
谈判筹码 厉害啊
Bargaining chip. Cool.
我从没当过谈判筹码
I've never been a bargaining chip before.
我当过猪队友 拖油瓶
I've been a liability. A disappointment.
-当过累赘 -我的飞船到了没
- A deduction. - Are we almost to my ship?
快了 我还当过枕头 怪咖
Not far now. I've also been a pillow, an enigma,
麻烦精 捣蛋鬼
a problem, a headache.
帮帮忙 拜托
Little help, please.
最近大家都无视我
Lately, I've just been ignored,
但这次我爸一定会注意到我
but now my dad's finally going to pay attention to me.
你家人关心你吗
Do your parents pay attention to you?
我姑妈奥嘉不关心我
Well, my Aunt Olga doesn't care.
只要送走我 她就能做想做的事
With me out the way she can do what she really wants.
比如当宇航员之类的
Like be an astronaut or whatever.
她为你放弃了当宇航员
She gave up being an astronaut or whatever for you?
哇 她一定很爱你
Wow. She must really love you.
不 她不爱我
No, no, she doesn't.
但现在我有机会加入宇宙联盟
But now I'm free to join the Communiverse,
一个真正属于我的地方
which is where I belong anyway
所以我全靠你了…
and that's where you come in,
谈判筹码
bargaining chip.
扭啊扭
Wiggle, wiggle.
索利斯候选人 抱歉打扰
Candidate Solís? Sorry to bother you.
只是高拿族飞船…
It's just that the Hylurgian ships
好像把炮口对准了联盟
seem to be pointing their cannons at us.
这是谈判流程
Is this part of the negotiations?
只是演习 别担心
Oh, that's just a drill. Don't worry.
扭啊扭
Wiggle.
快走
Come on.
这些管道是干嘛的
What are these tunnels for, anyway?
是熔岩槽 开炮时用的
Oh, these are the lava flumes. They power the cannons.
歌尔顿 我不防火啊
Glordon, I am not fireproof!
-是吗 你怎么不早说 -歌尔顿
- Really? Why didn't you say something? - Glordon!
没事 爬进我嘴里
It's okay. Just get in my mouth.
啊 不要
What? No way!
相信我
Trust me.
里面还挺舒服的
It's actually kind of comfy in here.
这是什么地方 我从没进来过…坐稳了
It is? I've never been in there. Hold on.
太好玩了
Yeah!
好刺激啊
Refreshing.
你没事吧
You okay?
太棒了
Yes!
放我下去
Lower me down.
谢谢你 歌尔顿
Thanks, Glordon.
小意思 击个掌吧
It's nothing. Up top.
要飞多久 机上有零食吗
How long's the flight? Any snacks on board?
是索利斯候选人 我肯定他会带来好消息
It's Candidate Solís! I'm sure he's bringing good news.
当心
Look out!
我好兴奋 我好兴奋啊
I'm so excited. I'm so excited. I'm so excited.
-索利斯候选人 -搞什么鬼
- Candidate Solís? - What's happened?
噢噢噢 快联系格尔钢勋爵
Ooooo, open a line to Lord Grigon!
-没问题 -这位是
- Of course. - Who is this?
到底是谁…
Who is responsible for...
-你 -没错
- You! - Yes.
就是我 地球的领袖
It's me! The leader of Earth.
而且谈判还没结束 因为现在我有了…他
And the negotiation is not over because now I've got this!
天啊
Oh, my.
歌尔顿
Glordon?
没错 而且很快 歌尔顿就会永远消失
Yes, and pretty soon he's going to be Glor- done.
嗨 爸爸 我是谈判筹码
Hi, Dad. I'm a bargaining chip.
不对 换句台词
No. Say the other thing.
救救我 爸爸 他控制住我了
Help me, Father. He overpowered me.
他力气太大…而且块头好大
He's too strong. Too shredded.
你闭嘴啦
Quiet, you!
什么声音这么难听 快停下
What is that unholy sound? Stop! Stop!
你要发誓…
Only if you swear...
以高拿族的名誉发誓
On your Hylurgian honor.
On your Hylurgian honor
和平离开宇宙联盟 永远不再回来
to leave the Communiverse in peace and never return.
我的高拿族名誉
My Hylurgian honor?
你知道你在要求什么吗 我会…
Do you know what you are asking? I will...
够了
Stop!
我认输
I concede!
我以名誉起誓…
I swear on my honor...
你真是出乎我意料
You are full of surprises.
你得到我的承诺
You have my vow.
我会来接我儿子
I will come to collect my son,
但要是我儿子少了一根汗毛
but if even one hair on a single nub is harmed,
你就会见识我的怒火
you will feel my wrath.
干得好 早知道你有这本事
Well done. I knew you had it in you.
过奖了
Thank you.
我巴不得赶快解决这事 正式欢迎你加入
Oh, I can't wait for this all to be over, and officially welcome you into the fold.
我马上给你定制会员徽章
I'm customizing your membership badge right now.
喜欢这个颜色吗
Do you like the color?
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
而且你完全配得上
And so well- deserved.
但首先 大家得准备迎接格尔钢勋爵
But first, let's prepare for Lord Grigon's arrival.
来吧 各位…快点
Come, everyone. Chop chop.
你们先走 我得搞定谈判筹码
You guys go ahead. I'll take care of the bargaining chip.
好啊 索利斯候选人 哪家餐厅好吃
Very good, Candidate Solís. Now, does anyone know a good caterer?
我们成功了
Oh, we did it.
没错 你超帅的
Yeah. You were so cool.
你没事吧
Oh, you okay?
我从没去过外面
I've never been outside before.
这里太冷了
It's cold here.
哇 这装置太牛了
Wow! This thing's amazing.
看好了…重力关闭
Watch this. Gravity off.
重力关闭
Gravity off.
这就觉得厉害了 跟我来
You think this is cool? Come on!
勋爵 接驳艇已备妥 出发吗
Your Wrath, the shuttle is ready. Shall we depart?
不 再等等
No, not yet.
小王子被掳全因他懦弱
The princeling was taken because he was vulnerable...
缺乏戒备 心太软
exposed, soft.
给他准备好装甲外壳
Prepare his carapace.
但这需要时间 嗜血殿下
But that will take time, Your Bloodness...
立刻去 我们要在宇宙联盟 为歌尔顿举行仪式
Do it! We will perform Glordon's ceremony on the Communiverse
让他们见识高拿族的厉害 准能吓破胆
and they will quiver at the full might of Hylurg!
-准备好了 -好了
- Ready? - Yes.
还没呢
No.
好了…可以了
Okay, yes!
数到三
On three.
一 二…
One, two...
-两秒半 -两秒半
- Two and a half. - Two and a half.
三
Three!
-再来一次 -必须的
- Again? - Heck, yeah, again.
-数到三 -一 二
- On three. - One, two.
超好玩
Yeah!
不会吧
No, no.
酷毙了
Noice.
所有地球人都会说艾力奥语
So, everyone speaks Elioese on Earth?
不 只有我会
Nah, just me.
还有我父母
And my parents.
至少以前会
Or at least they did.
我姑妈就没兴趣
My aunt's not into it,
但我会一直说 因为不想忘记
but I keep using it so I don't forget.
你父母出事了对吗
Did something happen to your parents?
是的
Yeah.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我知道情况不同 但我妈妈也总不在身边
I know it's not the same, but my mom's gone a lot.
她总去打仗
Fighting the Blood Wars.
我很想她
I miss her a ton.
有时候觉得 爸爸根本不在乎我
Sometimes it feels like Dad doesn't even want me.
我懂这种感觉
I know what you mean.
世上唯一在乎我的人已经不在了
The only people who wanted me are gone.
但我不确定
But I don't know.
如果…
What if...
是我不值得被在乎呢
What if there's nothing about me to want?
我还以为是地球有问题…
I thought Earth was the problem...
但万一是我的问题呢
but what if it's me?
我喜欢你呀
Well, I like you.
我觉得你挺好的
And you seem fine to me.
他带了你的铠甲来
He brought your carapace.
好像是
I guess so?
但这算好事 对吧
But that's good, right?
当然好 铠甲有火焰喷射器 还有圆锯 酸液枪
Yeah. I mean, it has a flame thrower, a circular saw, acid gun.
我可以穿着去战斗 侵略 杀戮…
I'll get to fight, and conquer, and kill, and...
歌尔顿
Glordon,
你其实不想穿铠甲
do you not want to get into your carapace?
想啊…应该想吧…
Yeah, I mean, kind of, well...
不想…根本不想
No, no.
我一直假装想穿 其实是在骗自己
I've been pretending to want it, but I've been living a lie!
一穿上就再也不能玩耍 游泳
Once I'm installed, I'll never get to play, or swim,
什么都做不了
or do anything.
那样太惨了
It'll be the worst!
为什么不说出来
But why didn't you say something?
因为所有高拿族都必须穿
Because all Hylurgians have to do it!
这是传统
It's tradition.
如果我拒绝…
And if I don't,
爸爸会恨死我的
my dad would hate me.
歌尔顿 你可以不穿
Glordon, you're not getting in there.
但我没得选啊
But I don't have a choice.
一起想办法
We'll figure it out.
虽然还没头绪 不过…
I don't know how, but...
等等
Oh, wait.
干嘛
What?
要干嘛
What are we doing?
给你爸爸最想要的东西
We're going to give your dad what he wants.
我
Me?
是 但也不是
Well, yes, but also no.
复制泥 你确定能行
Cloning clay? Are you sure about this?
肯定行 难道不行吗
Yeah. Why not?
不知道啊 复制品真能骗过我爸爸
I don't know. Would a clone really fool my dad?
我爸很精明的
He's pretty smart.
绝对可以 我演示给你看
It's going to work. I'll show you.
呜噜噜 呜噜噜
Ooooo? Ooooo?
-在 -我想看看我的复制体
- Yes? - Can I check on my clone?
没问题
Certainly.
闻着真香啊小子
That smells good, papito.
独家配方
It's a secret recipe.
你肯定会喜欢
You're going to love it.
你怎么什么都懂
How are you so good at everything?
哇 好像真的可行
Wow. I guess it does work.
好吧 那就试试
Okay, let's do it.
好啊
Yeah.
搞定
Yeah!
这样你爸就会把复制品带回高拿星
Okay. Your dad will take your clone back to Hylurg,
我就能当大使了
I'll become an Ambassador,
我和你以后不用再回高拿星
and neither of us will have to see Hylurg,
或者那个破地球
or stupid Earth again.
简直是三赢
It's a win- win- win.
完美
Yes.
我叫歌尔顿
I'm Glordon!
哇 我真的这么大只
Wow! Am I really that ripped?
你 跟着来
You, follow us.
明白
You got it.
你躲进去就安全了 没人能打开
You'll be safe in here. No one else can open it.
好了 歌尔顿 进太空船吧
All right, Glordon, get in the ship.
明白
Okay.
我分不清你俩
I can't tell you apart.
厉害
Yes!
说真的 哪个是正版
Seriously, though, which one's real?
我
Me.
躲进去 别出声
Stay inside and don't make a sound.
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
走吧
Come on.
你好逼真啊 我完全看不出区别
You look so good. I can't even tell the difference.
我完全尝不出区别
I can't even tell the difference.
我就说吧
I know.
谁能想到用酸奶代替黄油一样好吃
Who knew yogurt is just as yummy as butter,
而且胆固醇少一半
and half the cholesterol?
太棒了
It's perfect.
我帮你收碟子
Let me get that for you.
谢谢
Thanks so much.
我回房睡了
Well, I'm going to turn in for the night.
好啊 但你过来一下 小子
All right. But first, get over here, kiddo.
晚安
Good night.
绑架 洗脑 妖精 朋友 你哪位
艾力奥活动记录
《你被绑架 外星人绑架实录》
怎么会这样
What the?
嗨 不如大家聊聊
Hi. We should probably talk.
我下一个表演…你猜个数字
And for my next trick, think of a number.
等等
Wait.
好 猜到了
Okay, got it!
行…知道了
Yes, yes, yes.
我不知道还能拖延多久
I don't know how much longer we can stall.
索利斯候选人呢
Where is Candidate Solís?
我肯定他马上到
I'm sure he'll be here momentarily.
我感应到的数字是…
I sense the number is
-七 -啊
- seven. - What?
-猜中了 -够了
- She's right. - Enough!
我儿子呢
Where is my son?
在这 他在这
He's here. He's right here.
爸爸
Daddy.
-他没有背叛联盟 -他来了
- He did not abandon us. - He's here!
谢天谢地
Thank the stars.
格尔钢勋爵 歌尔顿王子还给你
Lord Grigon, we return to you Prince Glordon.
孩子…他们伤害你了吗
My son. Did he harm you?
没有 大家都超级友善
Nope. Everyone was super nice.
准备好成为全宇宙最强的战斗机器了吗
Are you prepared to become
让敌人见到你就吓得发抖
the greatest war machine in the universe?
证明高拿族有多…
To make your enemies tremble at the sight of you?
行了 开始吧
To prove the might of the...
其实我还有很多没讲 但好吧 马上开始
Yep! Let's do it!
太棒了
Actually, I had more to say, but, yes, let us get on with it.
幸好
Oh, yeah.
见证高拿星的力量
Witness the power of Hylurg.
见证吧
Witness!
-太精彩了 -太厉害了
- What a good show. - Very impressive.
那就好
That's right.
既然各位守信用
As you have kept your word,
我也会遵守承诺 永远离开联盟不再回来
I will keep mine and leave this place never to return.
高拿族 撤退
Hylurgians, fall back.
索利斯候选人 你成功了
Candidate Solís, you did it!
干得好
Well done.
真是了不起啊
What an exceptional specimen.
没事吧 孩子
You good, son?
没事啊 我可期待不停打仗了
Oh, yeah. I can't wait to make endless war
掠夺无用的星球 带来永恒黑暗…
and pillage the unworthy and bring eternal night...
我有幸加入宇宙联盟吗
May I have the honor of joining the Communiverse?
联盟才深感荣幸 索利斯候选人
The honor would be ours, Candidate Solís.
我或许该改口叫你…索利斯大使
Or should I say, Ambassador Solís.
你正式成为会员了
You're one of us now.
-我喜欢你 -欢迎
- I like you. - Welcome!
原来是复制品
It was a clone.
我儿子呢
Where is my son?
不过…
But...
你怎么发现的
How could you tell?
当爸爸的…一定能分辨
A father always knows.
你 读取他大脑
You, read his mind.
找出真相
Find the truth.
不要啊
No.
放开我
Unhand me!
非常对不起
I'm so sorry.
不要
No.
不要啊
求求你不要
No, no, no, please. No!
怎样 看到什么
What? What did you see?
你儿子躲进了停泊区的外交船
Your son is in a diplomatic ship in the docking bay.
派军队过去
Send the troops!
再吃个布丁吧 艾力奥
Oh, more pudding, Elio?
谢谢你 歌尔顿
Why, thank you, Glordon!
艾力奥
Elio?
你已选择我方坐标地图
You have selected a map of our coordinates.
颈枕 润唇膏 薄荷糖
Neck pillow. Lip balm. A breath mint.
目的地
Destination?
地…地球
Uh, Earth.
确认 还是取消
Confirm or cancel?
啊 确认
What? Confirm?
好 立刻开启通往地球的通道
Ooooo, open a portal to Earth.
你想干什么
What are you doing?
你自己说 还是我来说
Will you tell them, or must I?
求求你别这样
Please don't.
他不是地球的领袖
He is not the leader of Earth.
-什么 -根本不是什么领袖
- What? - He is not the leader of anything.
他只是…
He is just
一个孩子
a child.
-啊 -糟了
- What? - Oh, no.
-我不明白 -不是这样的
- I do not understand. - No.
她搞错了
She's wrong.
我就是地球的领袖
I am the leader of Earth.
我还能帮上忙
I can still help!
求求大家…让我留下
Just please, please let me stay.
我儿子不见了
He is not there!
-什么 -可我明明看见
- What? - But I saw him!
我们都和你一样震惊
We are as surprised as you.
扣押整个联盟 宇宙联盟现在由高拿族接管
Arrest them all! The Communiverse is now under Hylurgian control.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
有事好商量
We can sort this out!
都是他的错 与我们无关
It's his fault, not ours!
骗子 背信弃义 懦夫
Liar! Betrayer! Coward!
快走 立刻离开
Leave! Now!
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你惹的麻烦够多了
You've done enough!
不要
No!
翻遍整个联盟 直到找到我儿子为止
Tear this place apart until you find my son!
糟糕
No.
别丢下我
Don't leave me.
求你了
Please.
我帮你拿
Oh, I'll take that.
谢谢 孩子
Thanks, kiddo.
糟了 我忘带…那个…
Shoot. I left the... That...
-我知道 马上回来 -拜托
- I know what it is. Be right back. - Thank you.
你也找不到 扔过来给我
You couldn't find it, huh? Would you toss me those?
亮了
Come on!
破烂手电筒
Stupid flashlight!
对不起
Sorry.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
有事…我快疯了
No. I feel crazy!
我在沙滩试图联系不明外星人
I'm on the beach trying to make contact with I don't know what.
我真的…
I just...
觉得好…
feel so...
孤独
alone.
你不会懂的
You wouldn't understand.
其实…
Actually,
我懂啊
I do.
外星人 带他回来!
我以为你不会想我
I didn't think you'd miss me.
我很想你
I missed you.
你的一切…我都很想念
I've missed everything about you.
但你不该过这样的人生
But this isn't the life you wanted.
我唯一想要的…
The only thing I want
就是你
is you.
奥嘉姑姐
Tía Olga!
嘿 你回来啦
Oh, hey, you're back!
基地好像出大事了
Something's going on at the base.
等等 我的太空船
Wait. That's my spaceship.
-歌尔顿在里面 -谁说的
- Glordon's in there! - Who?
我朋友
My friend.
-你交到朋友 -厉害啊
- You made a friend? - Nice.
没错 他需要帮助 你有进入许可吗
Yeah, and he needs our help. You have clearance, right?
我哪有这么高级
Not for this.
肯定有办法进去的
There's got to be some way to get in there.
好了…让我想想
Okay, okay. Let me think.
如果两位不需要我了 我就启动自动分解程序
Well, if you don't need me anymore, I will begin my decomposition process.
两位可以把我撒在植物上当肥料
Feel free to spread me over a plant as nutritious fertilizer.
等等
Wait!
说过是什么情况吗
They mention what it is?
没有 但异象解析部和太空总署正赶来
Negative. But AARO's here and NASA's on the way.
难道是…外星人
Is it extraterrestrial?
你说小绿人 你不会真信吧
What, like little green men? Don't tell me you believe in that stuff.
谁啊
Who's there?
是个小孩
It's a kid.
嘿 你不准进来
Hey, you shouldn't be here.
能帮帮我吗
Can you help me?
我有点不舒服
I don't feel so good.
拉开他
Get it off me!
快把他拉开
弹进我嘴里了
It's in my mouth!
怎么是酸的
Why is it sour?
沾到我身上了
It's on me too!
救命啊
Help! Help!
感谢你的牺牲
Thank you for your service.
歌尔顿
Glordon!
你朋友
Is that your friend?
艾力奥
Elio?
你怎么在这儿
What are you doing here?
你又怎么在这儿
我叫你躲好的
Why didn't you stay where I told you?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不小心启动了太空船
I accidentally turned on the ship.
歌尔顿 歌尔顿
Glordon? Glordon.
-他病了 -他的控制器坏了
- Is he sick? - His disc is broken.
这里对他来说太冷了
It's too cold for him here!
嘿
Hey!
举起手来 远离那个样本
Put your hands up! Back away from the specimen.
我命令你们两个退后 立刻
I said, back away! Now!
你懂艾力奥语吗
You learned Elioese?
数到三就扔冰淇淋
冰淇淋
你俩在说什么
Hey, what are you saying?
冰淇淋 冰淇淋啊
头盔
-哦 你说清楚点嘛 -够了
- Oh, you mean "Glöp." - Stop that!
三
踩油门
Gun it!
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
实在太…
This is so...
厉害了
Oh, my gosh.
撑住 歌尔顿 奥嘉 你来开飞船
Hold on, Glordon. Olga, you got to drive!
-怎么开啊 -拜托了
- But how? - Please!
欢迎你 临时船长
Welcome, guest pilot!
把你外套给我
Give me your jacket.
对不起 歌尔顿 都是我的错
I'm so sorry, Glordon. This is all my fault.
你放心
Don't worry.
我会送你回家
I'm going to get you home.
飞船 前往宇宙联盟
Ship, get us to the Communiverse.
无法启动超空间飞行 航线受阻
Hyper- speed unavailable, path blocked.
啥 明明没障碍
What? It's totally clear.
系统说"无法启动超空间飞行 航线受阻"
I said, "Hyper- speed unavailable, path blocked."
搞什么鬼
Oh, come on!
怎么了
What?
我们在太空垃圾带
We're in a debris field.
-快冲出去 -不行
- Let's just get out of here. - No!
-那些垃圾比子弹还快 -这不该是你的专长吗
- These objects are faster than bullets. - But this is what you do.
我是地面分析员
From the ground.
不知道垃圾的具体方位
I don't know where the debris's coming from.
需要高度 速度数据…
I need altitudes, velocity...
能联系基地就好了
If I could just contact someone on the ground.
但基地通讯被封锁了
But the base is on lockdown.
或者任何有无线电的人都行…我乱说的
Maybe someone with a Ham radio. I don't know!
艾力奥
Elio?
兄弟 我早说UFO是真的
Bro, I bet that UFO was real.
如果外星人来找食物 却只吃仓鼠呢
What if they're here for food and the only thing they eat are hamsters?
我无所谓啊
I'm fine with that.
PXLOL 请回复
PXLOL, please respond.
PXLOL 回复
PXLOL, come in!
喂 我是PXLOL
Hello? This is PXLOL.
布斯
Bryce!
我是艾力奥
This is Elio.
索利斯
Solís?
之前的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about what happened.
加纳人有时确实讨厌
Caleb can be a real butt sometimes.
没关系 我有时也讨人厌
It's okay, I was a butt too.
听着 你可能不信 但我们在外星飞船上
Look, you might not believe this, but we're in an alien ship that just...
原来是你们 太酷了 无线电圈都在传
That's you? Aw, man! There's a lot of radio chatter about that.
没错 我们需要穿越太空垃圾带
Yeah, that's us. We're trying to fly through debris,
但得先确定太空垃圾方位
but we need to know where it's coming...
你数学好吗 物理在行吗
How's your math? Physics? Are you good at physics?
布斯 我急需你帮忙
Bryce, I really need your help.
求你了
Please.
我不太懂什么太空垃圾
I don't know anything about debris,
但我知道有个专家
but I know someone who does.
他是我无线电群的传奇人物
He's a legend in my radio group.
是带头大哥 外号"天眼通"他…
The boss. The eyes in the sky. He's...
阿唛前来报到
Melmac reporting for duty!
交给我吧 PXLOL
I'll take it from here, PXLOL!
艾力奥 你必须完完整整地回来 好吗
Elio, you better come back in one piece, okay?
回头再跟你细说
I'll tell you all about it.
谢谢你 阿唛 我欠你个大人…
Thank you, Melmac, I owe you a huge...
别客气 少校
Never mind that, Major.
朋友有难 阿唛绝不推辞
A Master of Ham always helps in a jam.
我来帮你穿越碎片带
Let's get you through this debris field.
正在接入系统…准备就绪
I'm pulling up the network now. Get ready.
需要锁定固定坐标
We need a fixed target.
猎户座腰带
Orion's belt.
完美 朝那个方向直飞
Perfect. Drive straight toward it,
-准备规避垃圾 -收到
- and be ready to dodge. - Okay.
飞船 能投射坐标网格吗
Ship, can you project a grid?
怎么样 阿唛 有发现吗 快 我们马上要脱离通讯范围了
Okay. Melmac, anything out there! Hurry, before we're out of range!
找到了 大型火箭残骸
Okay. Large rocket body!
海拔高度407公里
Altitude, 407 kilometers,
时速7.66
velocity, 7.66.
收到
Got it.
就在那儿
There.
哪儿 我看不见
Where? I don't see it!
快后退 立刻
Just pull back. Now!
又出现一个 788公里 时速7.46
Another one! 788 kilometers, velocity, 7.46.
-急速爬升 马上 -明白
- Climb fast! Now! - Roger!
这回稳了
We are going ham.
干得漂亮
You're doing great.
阿唛 继续汇报
Melmac, keep them coming.
少校 你即将脱离通讯范围 别切换频道
Major, you're leaving the com window. Just stay on this frequency.
不要切换…频道
Stay... Frequency...
阿唛 阿咦
Melmac? Melmac?
防护罩剩余80%
Shields at 80%.
歌尔顿
Glordon.
有人听到吗
Is anyone there?
有人听到吗 求救 求救
Please, anyone? Mayday! Mayday! Come in. Come in!
防护罩剩余60%
Shields at 60%.
防护罩剩余41%
Shields at 41%.
防护罩剩余23%
Shields at 23%.
求救 求救 请回答
Mayday! Mayday! Come in. Come in!
−喂 -防护罩剩余16%
- Hello? - Shields at 16%.
-有人听见吗 -只剩我们了
Is anyone out there?
有人听见吗
Can anyone hear us?
…塞内加尔
...Senegal.
你好 我是塞内加尔的业余无线电高手
Bonjour. This is Masters of Ham in Senegal.
听到 我们听到
Yes, yes. We read you.
太空垃圾距离你们1300公里 速度7.2
Large debris at 1,300 kilometers, velocity, 7.2.
拉后 全力拉
Pull back! Hard!
多谢 多谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
高手很乐意为你们效劳
Masters of Ham at your service.
我是来自意大利的朱利亚
This is Giulia from Italia.
太好了
This is awesome!
-高度2224 速度6.81 -右边
- 2224, velocity 6.81. - Right.
我是亚美尼亚的阿努什
This is Anoush in Armenia.
-速度6.75 -右边
- Velocity, 6.75. - Right!
你好
Namaste.
-我来自孟买 -爬升
- This is Vikram from Mumbai. - Climb!
太空垃圾高度2753
Debris at 2,753,
-速度6.61 -左
- velocity, 6.61. - Left!
-我是越南的黄仔 -速度6…
- This is Hoang in Vietnam. - ...velocity, 6...
你们好 我来自日本
Konnichiwa from Japan.
-你们可以的 -你们会没事的
- You can do this! - You're going to be okay.
-有大家陪着你 -加油啊 老友
- You're not alone. - Hey, come on, buddy!
-上啊 -加油 小子
- Go, go, go! - Come on, kid!
−继续前进 -快到了
- Keep going! - You're almost there!
还有一件 避开 避开
There's one more piece! Move, move!
-哪里 -不知道啊
- Which way? - I don't know.
路线畅通
Path cleared.
歌尔顿
Glordon?
启动超空间飞行
Engaging hyper- speed.
帮帮忙 拜托
Help us. Please.
-艾力奥 -歌尔顿 不要啊
- Elio. - Glordon. No!
放开我
Get off me!
歌尔顿
Glordon.
歌尔顿 醒醒
Glordon, wake up.
不要啊
No.
我不能再失去你
I can't lose you too.
不要啊
No!
你们两个解释清楚
Explain yourselves.
我不会说
I can't.
直接告诉他
Just tell him.
你爸爸很爱你的
He loves you.
你看他多想你回来
Look how much he wanted you back.
我不想当战斗机器
I don't want to be a war machine.
你早就知道
You already know?
没错
Yes.
我或许不是事事都理解你
I may not always understand you,
但我依然爱你
but I still love you.
我包得太松 没你妈妈手艺好
It's a loose swaddle. I do not have your mother's touch.
你包得很好
You did great.
我从未说过以下几个字 但…
I have never uttered these words before,
我很抱歉
but I am sorry.
释放整个联盟
Release them all.
恭喜 索利斯大使
Congratulations, Ambassador Solís!
但我撒谎骗了大家
But I lied to you!
之后你却愿意牺牲自己去救别人
And then you sacrificed yourself to save another.
你的表现令人敬佩 就像真正的星球领袖
You behaved as admirably as any real planetary leader.
而且你带来了和平
And you did bring peace.
终于迎来安宁的日子
Eventually.
这个位置是你自己争取来的
You have earned your place here.
我可以留下吗
I could stay?
太棒了
Yes, yes, yes!
好极了
Excellent.
可以天天一起玩
We can hang out every day.
这里确实很美好
This place is amazing,
但地球才是…
but Earth is...
我的家
home.
从前我不愿接受
I didn't give it a chance
但现在
but now,
我想尝试
I want to try.
和你一起
With you.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我们是一家人
We're family.
这次不是永别
This isn't goodbye.
只是时机未到
It's just not yet.
我们都明自
We understand.
你真特别 地球的艾力奥
You are unique, Elio of Earth,
而"特别"有时会感到"孤独"
and "Unique" Can sometimes feel like "Alone."
但你绝不孤单
But you are not alone.
好啦
Okay.
拜拜
Bye.
我爱你
I love you.
好啦 拜拜 我爱你
Okay. Bye. I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
回家吧
Let's go home.
这是古老的人类命题
It's an ancient human theme.
几乎存在于所有文化中
You can find it in virtually every culture.
从宗教 民谣 迷信到现代科学
In religion, folklore, superstition, and, now, in science.
在这个时代寻找外星生命很特别
The search for life elsewhere is remarkable in our age
因为我们首次能付诸行动 而非空想
because this is the first time that we can actually do something besides speculation.
我们可以向邻近星球发射飞船
We can send spacecraft to nearby planets.
能用巨型射电望远镜
We can use large radio telescopes to see
监听最近的星际讯号
if there is any message being sent to us lately.
这一切都是为了解答人类最渴望知道的问题
And it touches to the deepest of human concerns.
人类是否孤单
Are we alone?
歌尔顿 你关机了吗
Glordon, your disc is muted.
噢 对不起
Oops, sorry.
全都告诉我吧
Now, tell me everything.
Merged by Anita
感谢《外星奇遇记》团队的亲友们
谢谢你们带我们回家